Sathishkumar Thirumalai

LinkedIn | GitHub | Kaggle

Location: Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India Email: sathishkumartheta@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-7845683031

MACHINE LEARNING RESEARCHER

I am a highly skilled engineer and a passionate problem solver with over 10 years of experience. I have designed and developed embedded systems, software systems and machine learning systems for solving problems in various domains such as RFID, Biometrics, and Medical imaging. Currently pursuing research (Ph.D.) on generalization of deep learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : python, c, c++, c#
Frameworks : pytorch, keras

Libraries : pandas, numpy, matplotlib, scikit-learn, opency

Databases : MSSQL, Sqlite

Dev Tools : Jupyter, Visual Studio Code, Git, Huggingface, Weights and Biases, Kaggle, Google Colab,

Github Codespace, AWS Sagemaker Studiolab, Roboflow, Ultralytics, MLFlow

EXPERIENCE

Embedded software developer	Nov 2012 – Dec 2015
Indira Gandhi Centre for Atomic Research (IGCAR)	Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
Python developer	Dec 2015 – Dec 2020
Indira Gandhi Centre for Atomic Research (IGCAR)	Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
Machine learning Engineer Indira Gandhi Centre for Atomic Research (IGCAR)	Jan 2021 – Present Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

EDUCATION

Sri Siva Subramaniya Nadar College of Engineering Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication	2007 – 2011 Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India
Homi Bhabha National Institute (HBNI) Master of Science	2015 – 2018 Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

PROJECTS

Camouflage Object Detection

pytorch, hugging face, weights and biases

Source Code

- Created a dataset and dataloader in pytorch for COD 10K dataset and performed exploratory data analysis using **pytorch and weights and biases**
- Deployed the state of the art model SINET for demonstration using gradio

Kaggle Icecube Neutrino direction estimation

pytorch, kaggle, weights and biases

Source Code

- Designed a machine learning model using transformers for performing regression on sequential data
- Submitted the model to the kaggle competition

Kaggle Image Matching Challenge 2023

pytorch, kaggle, weights and biases

Source Code

- Designed and trained deep learning models for rotation matrix and translation vector estimation.
- Submitted the model to the kaggle competition

Kaggle HubMAP2023 Kidney Segmentation Challenge pytorch, kaggle, weights and biases Source Code

- Designed and trained deep learning models such as maskrcnn, fastrcnn, yolov7, yolov8 for kidney image segmentation to detect blood vessels.
- Submitted the model to the kaggle competition (Ranked 400 out of 1000)

OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

CERTIFICATIONS